是我们的错  萨姆
We did this, Sam.
我们闯的祸  我们兜着
We broke it, we bought it.
我释放了一股能摧毁一切的力量到这世上
I unleashed a force on this world that could destroy it.
我只知道是我们放了她
All I know is that we set her free,
那我们就得把她关回去  不管付出什么代价
and we're gonna put her back in, no matter what it takes.
(走过的路)
为了创造世界  上帝
In order to create the world, God,
只能放弃黑暗  他的妹妹
he had to betray the darkness -- his sister.
那是怎么回事
What was that?
未来  我们是紧密相连的
The future. We're bonded.
你是释放了我的人
You're the one who set me free.
不  那只是个意外
No, that was an accident.
那是命运
It was destiny.
我是不可抗拒的
I can't be resisted.
地狱里有个笼子
There's this cage in hell,
路西法被关在里面
and it's where they keep Lucifer.
我也曾被关在里面
And I've been in it,
上帝好像想让我回到那里
and I think God wants me to go back.
他好有男人味啊
He's so alpha.
进入你头脑的并不是上帝  萨姆
It wasn't God inside your head, Sam.
是我
It was me.
他从未与你同在
He's never been with you.
一直都是我
It was always just me.
我想我的确是你唯一的希望
I guess I am your only hope.
绝不可能
It's never gonna happen.
那就住下吧  伙计
Settle in there, buddy.
(如今)
天呐
Boy, oh, boy.
妈妈  妈妈  我收到个萨姆
Mom! Mom, I got a Sam!
好啊  亲爱的
Good for you, dearie.
圣诞老人
Santa!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
你给我带来了什么  你给我带来了什么
What'd you bring me? What'd you bring me?
看看圣诞老人给你带了什么
Let's see what santa got for you today.
但是...
But...
我是个乖孩子啊
I was a good boy.
不是吧  罗威娜
Really, Rowena?
你就梦这个
This is what you dream about?
是反复出现的噩梦差不多
It's more of a recurring nightmare, actually.
这东西摘不掉
These don't come off.
这梦我已经做了几个月了
I've been having this dream for months,
但你
but you...
你是新的
you're new.
你是谁
Who are you?
嗯  抱歉  我的礼貌有点生疏了
Yeah, sorry, ‭my manners are a bit rusty.
[邪恶力量 第11季第10集]
你
You. ‭
幻觉
The visions.
一切
Everything.
都是你
It was all you.
厉害吧
Impressive, right?
罗威娜呢
And Rowena?
她只是听命行事
Did as she was told.
粉丝啊  总那么急切
Groupies... they're always so eager.
你做了那么多
So you did all of that just to...
就为了要我的身体吗
To what? Jump my bones?
没错
Literally.
那你白费功夫了
Well, you wasted your time, then.
我知道这事会怎么结局
'cause, see, I know how this ends.
是吗
Oh, do you, now?
是的
Yeah.
你戏弄我  折磨我
You'll taunt me, and you'll torture me,
我会拒绝
and I'll say no,
最终  比你想得要早
and eventually, sooner than you think,
我哥哥会走进来  揍扁你
my brother's gonna walk through that door and kick your ass.
迪恩
Dean?
你要把注压在迪恩身上
You're betting on Dean?
一向如此
I always have.
萨姆  你猜错我了
Oh, Sam, you got me all wrong.
我很怀疑
Yeah, I doubt that.
不  我并不打算折磨你
Oh, no. I-I'm not here to torture ya.
我是可以那么做
I mean, I could.
我可以给你痛苦
I could inflict pain
你无法想象的痛苦
‭like you can't even imagine.
我可以让你
I could inflict such delicious,
痛不欲生
perfect pain.
但那是五年前的我了
But that was so five years ago.
不  我不会伤你一根
No, I'm not gonna harm a glorious little hair
漂亮的汗毛的
on that glorious little head.
那你想怎么样
Then, what do you want?
提出一个你不忍拒绝的提议
To make you an offer you can't refuse.
你瞧  萨姆  你需要我
You see, Sam, you need me.
我会证明给你看
And I'm gonna prove it to you.
认得吗
Recognize it?
什么
What?
我们在一段记忆中  萨姆
We're in a memory, Sam.
你童年为数不多的一段好记忆
One of the few good ones from your childhood.
对了  我还觉得自己有恋父情结呢  可你呢
By the way, I thought I had daddy issues, but you?
总之  你应该能认得
Anyway, I think you recognize
那个帅气年轻的小伙子吧
the dashing young beanpole over there.
那是我
That's me.
你死定了
You're dead.
拜托  费格斯  少放空话了
Please, Fergus, enough with idle threats.
你背叛了我  还是在我的王国里
You betrayed me... in my kingdom.
不是你的  是他的
Not yours, his!
地狱是他的
Hell is his!
我也是他的
I'm his.
你伤了我  你觉得他会怎么整你
So hurt me, and what do you think he'll do to you?
路西法永远别想出牢笼
Lucifer will never get out of that cell.
你愿拿性命打赌吗
Are you willing to stake your life on that?
把注压在萨姆·温彻斯特身上
On Sam Winchester?!
多久了
How long?
你为他卖命多久了
How long have you been working for him?
没多久
Not long.
路西法给我托了梦
Lucifer came to me in a dream.
不是那种梦啦
Not that kind of dream.
你就打算让大猛男指使你吗
So, you're just gonna let the big, strong man boss you around?
你那个超屌巫师团呢
Whatever happened to the super-duper awesome coven?
还有女生力量呢
Girlpower?
路西法不是凡人
Lucifer's no man.
他是完美
He's perfection.
你以为我为什么让你的狗腿子找到我
Why do you think I let your droogs find me?
路西法有个计划
Lucifer has a plan, and...
他是魔鬼
And he's the devil.
你说得好像那是坏事似的
You say that like it's a bad thing.
我才是坏事
Oh, I'm a bad thing.
他是最糟的事
He's a worse thing.
路西法上次去人间
The last time Lucifer went topside,
知道他想做什么吗
do you know what he wanted?
死亡  你死  我死
Death for you, for me,
每个人  每个恶魔都死
and every human, and every demon.
他变了
He's changed.
是啊  当然
Oh, yes, of course.
他只不过需要一个死三八爱他
All he needed was the love of a horrible woman.
你做这些  是为什么
So, and you're doing all this, why?
出于好心吗
Out of the goodness of your heart?
别傻了
Don't be daft.
路西法阻止了黑暗
After Lucifer stops the Darkness,
就会升入天堂  坐上王位
he'll ascend to his throne in heaven,
我会伴在他身侧  作为忠诚追随者
and I'll be by his side, a loyal follower.
王后吗
A queen?
不管你喜欢不喜欢  你知道我说得对
Like it or not, you know I'm right.
路西法以前跟黑暗斗过  他赢了
Lucifer fought the Darkness before, and he won.
除非  你兜里揣着上帝
So, unless you've got the almighty in your back pocket,
你还是坐下  闭嘴
I suggest you sit down, shut up,
让他开工吧
and let him work.
萨姆不能接听  他在除毛呢
Sam can't talk 'cause he's waxing, like, everything,
-留言吧  -哥们
- but leave a message and... - Dude,
你拿我手机做什么
what are you doing with my phone?
迪恩  别闹了
Dean. Come on.
打给我  马上
Call me... now.
感谢致电克劳力  地狱之王
Thank you for phoning Crowley, King of Hell.
恶魔交易  请按1
For demon deals, press 1.
报告目击红发贱婊罗威娜  请按2
To report a sighting of that ginger whore, Rowena, press 2.
迪恩
Dean.
你一喊我我就赶来了  你没事吧
I came as soon as you called. Are you all right?
小卡
Cass?
你有事
You're not all right.
显然的
Obviously.
我是怎么了
What's wrong with me?
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
你干什么...
What are you...
-把舌头伸出来  -什么
- Stick out your tongue. - What?
完事没有
Are we done?
没...
No, I...
我给你测测体温
Let me take your temperature.
别指望了
No, that's not gonna happen.
离事发地有多远
How far are we from the event?
-天使核弹吗  -对
- You mean the angel nuke? - Yeah.
原爆点是那个方向一英里远左右
Ground zero's about a mile down that way.
好吧  那就说得通了
Okay, that explains it.
你是患了毁灭晕眩
You're suffering from smiting sickness.
-还有这玩意  -是啊
- That's a thing? ‭- Yeah.
天使所做的事
The angels, what they did,
释放了很大量的能量
it released a tremendous amount of energy,
这是有后果的  这一整片区域都受到了毒害
and there's fallout, so this whole area is poisoned.
你能治好我吧
You can heal me, right?
我不能
No, I can't,
而且你越靠近原爆点
and the closer you get to the blast site,
你的晕眩越会加剧
the worse your sickness will become.
到什么程度
How worse?
上次发生这种程度的毁灭
The last time there was a smiting of this magnitude,
罗德之妻变成了盐
Lot's wife turned to salt.
好极了
Awesome.
好了  迪恩  你得回去
All right, Dean, you need to go back.
不行
Uh, no.
不行  我们得去看看是不是成功了
No, no, we got to... ‭we got to go see if it worked,
看看阿玛拉是死是活
See if Amara is alive or dead.
"我们"不用去
We don't.
这个后果对天使没影响  我自己去
The fallout doesn't affect angels. I'll go in alone.
好吧  那样或许更好
Okay, yeah, it's... ‭it's probably better that way.
我开车去看看萨姆
I'll take a drive. I'll go check on Sam.
好
Right.
好的
Good.
小卡
Hey, Cass?
如果真好使了  她死了
If it did work, and she is dead...
把她的尸体带出来
Bring her body out.
如果她没死呢
And if she's not?
那就快跑
Run.
阿芝特克祭司
So, the Aztec priests,
以为如果不进行人祭
they thought if they didn't sacrifice people,
世界就会终结
the whole world would end,
所以他们建造了好多庙宇
so they built all of these temples.
最棒的一个在墨西哥城
The most amazing ones are in Mexico City.
你去看过吗
Have you seen them?
去年  我爸带我和我哥去了墨西哥
Last year, my dad took me and my brother on a trip to Mexico.
去度假吗
On vacation?
算是工作度假吧
Kind of a working vacation.
你知道卓柏卡布拉吗
Have you ever heard of a Chupacabra?
不
No.
那就好
Okay, good. ‭
看啊  萨姆
Look at that, Sam.
边远小镇的单纯女孩
A simple girl from a one-stop-light town,
而你呢  见过世面
and you, the worldly,
还算帅气的萨姆·温彻斯特
handsome-ish Sam Winchester.
她根本毫无机会  记得吗
No, she didn't stand a chance. You remember?
嗯  你为什么...
Yeah. Why are you...
来了  嘘  这段最精彩了
Here. Shh, shh, shh. This is the best part.
萨姆
Sam...
你知道我带你来这儿不是为了学习吧
You know I didn't bring you here to study, right?
-不是吗  -不是
- You didn't? - ‭No.
我觉得你很聪明
I-I mean, I just think that you're smart
很风趣  很可爱
and funny and cute.
如果...你想亲热一下
So, I mean, if you want to make out...
就这个
That's it.
我说的就是这个
That's what I'm talking about right there, man.
接吻吗
Kissing?
不是  萨姆
No, Sam.
这是我记忆里的那个萨姆·温彻斯特
This is the Sam Winchester that I remember.
大胆  果决
Bold, decisive,
舌吻技能良
solid "B" on the tongue action.
你到底是想干什么
What is this about?
你以前是个英雄  萨姆
You used to be a hero, Sam.
你还打败过我
Hell, you beat me.
现在呢
Now?
我不知道  我看着你
I don't know. I look at you...
都认不出来了
I don't even recognize you anymore.
萨姆
Sam!
Sammy!
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
我也想你  小布丁
Miss you, too, puddin'.
你在哪  萨姆在哪
Where are you? Where's Sam?
出了点问题
There's a bit of a hiccup.
你弟弟跟路西法一起在地狱
Your brother's in hell with Lucifer.
(斯塔尔墓地)
斯塔尔墓地
Stull cemetery.
正确
Bingo.
世纪大战发生的地方
Where the title fight went down.
混球
Ass-butt!
混球  我到现在也不懂
Ass-butt? ‭I-I-I-I still don't get that.
多谢你带我回忆过去  但是
Look, I appreciate the stroll down memory lane, but...
萨姆  我有说过我多么敬重你吗
Sam, have I ever told you how much I respect you?
什么
What?
别误会  我并不喜欢你
Oh, don't get me wrong. I don't like you.
我从没喜欢过你
I've never liked you.
你太...谨小慎微了
You're... you're sort of prissy.
但在这一刻
But in this moment,
当你跟我正面对决  还赢了
when you stood toe-to-toe with me and won,
我得说  你真有种  小子
I got to say, you had balls, kid.
没事的  迪恩
It's okay, Dean.
没事了
It's gonna be okay.
我控制住他了
I got him.
你愿意为拯救世界
You were willing to do the hard thing
做出艰难的选择
if it meant saving the world.
不
No!
你现在已经不是那样了
That's not you anymore.
你心软了  萨姆
You've gone soft, Sammy.
你是谁
Who are you?
安布里奥
Ambriel.
我在天堂做生死统计
I work in birth/death statistics in heaven.
我是个天使
I-I'm an... I'm an angel.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
你是卡西迪奥吗
And you're Castiel?
我听过好多你的事
I've heard stories about you.
你来这儿干什么
Why are you here?
跟你的原因一样
Same reason you are.
天堂想知道黑暗是否已经被消灭
Heaven wants to know if ‭the Darkness has been destroyed?
差不多吧
Pretty much.
他们派你来
And they sent you?
你要杀我吗
Are you gonna kill me?
他们就这么说吗  我杀天使
Is that what they say, that I kill angels?
这算是最客气的了
Well, that's the nicest thing they say.
或许我们可以合作  谁都不用杀谁
Maybe we can work together, so no one murders anyone?
嗯
Right.
好吧
Fine.
好了  我已经搜过东边的林子了
Okay, so I've searched the east end of the forest.
没什么异常
Nothing weird.
是吗
Really?
你知道现在是大下午吗
You know it is ‭the middle of the afternoon.
那么...
So...?
那么  为什么这么黑
So... Why is it dark?
好问题
Excellent question.
小卡  我知道你在干正经事
Hey, Cass, I know you're fighting the good fight right now,
我需要你来内布拉斯加州肯纳索
but I need you at 3rd and Pine,
第三大道和派恩街口
Kenesaw, Nebraska.
我要下地狱了
'cause, uh, I'm going to hell.
口令
Password.
克劳力叫我来的  赶紧开门
Crowley sent me, all right? Just open up.
口令
Password.
不是吧
Really?
*坎普顿的妹子唱起来*
*Camptown ladies sing this song*
*嘟嘟哒*
*Doo dah, doo dah*
*坎普顿的跑道五英里长*
*Camptown racetrack five miles long*
*嘟嘟哒  嘟嘟迪*  快让我进去
*Oh, the doo-dah day* All right, just let me in.
唱得好  比伯
Nice work, Bieber.
你个恶魔还挺幽默
Funny for a demon.
不是恶魔  我叫比莉
Not a demon. Name's Billie.
死神比莉吗
The reaper Billie?
我弟弟说你想杀了我们
My brother says you want to kill us.
不
No.
我只是要确保等你们死了  不会再活过来
I'm just gonna make sure that when you die, you stay dead.
有些区别的
Subtle difference.
怎么  你为克劳力工作了吗
So what, you work for Crowley?
是合作  不是为他工作
With, not for.
现在世道不好  温彻斯特
It's strange days, Winchester.
这样的时候
Times like this...
让国王欠你个人情没什么不好
It doesn't hurt to have the king owe you a favor.
给那英国佬的
For the limey.
-是什么  -你会知道的
- What is it? - ‭You'll see.
管你呢
Whatever.
送我去我该去的地方吧
All right, just get me to where I need to go.
就这么打算的
That's the plan.
小心脚下
Watch your step.
路可长呢
It's a long way down.
想好你要跟他说什么了吗
Thought about what you're gonna say to him?
我想过了  我好好想过了
I've thought about it, and I've thought about it.
-我还是不知道  -一切都在这儿改变了  萨姆
- I still don't know. - Here's where it all changed, Sammy.
感觉好不真实
It's just all so surreal.
这是你做过的最糟的事
This is the worst thing you've ever done.
他知道他们告诉你他是行动中牺牲的吗
Does he know they told you he was killed in action?
是吗
Really?
利维坦事件之后
After the leviathans,
你哥哥被困在炼狱里
when your brother was trapped in purgatory,
你却在这儿泡妞  逗狗
you were here with a girl and a dog.
你根本没努力去找他
You didn't even bother trying to find him.
知道吗  我虽然不用向你证明什么
You know what? Not that I have to defend myself to you,
但迪恩和我说好我们不会再去找彼此了
But Dean and I promised we wouldn't look for each other.
是啊  如果他之后也没回来就没事了
Right, and if he never came back, you'd be fine.
但他回来了  所以有事
But he did, so you're not.
那个大胆  果决
Whatever happened to the Sam Winchester
甘为大局牺牲的
who was bold, decisive,
萨姆·温彻斯特呢
and ready to sacrifice for the greater good?
-就在这儿  -那你为什么听了迪恩的
- Right here. - ‭And so why did you let Dean
没有关闭地狱大门
talk you out of closing the gates of hell?
之前的萨姆可不会那么做  绝不会
'cause the old Sam never would've done that, not ever.
-我没...  -等等  这个我最喜欢
- I didn't... ‭- No, wait, ‭here's my personal favorite
你为了祛除血印做尽了蠢事
is you doing every stupid thing you could to cure the mark,
即便你知道不会有好结果
even after you knew it would go bad.
我哥哥要死了
My brother was dying.
是啊  你为了救他不惜一切
Yes, and you'd do anything to save him,
他也会为救你不惜一切
and he'd do anything to save you,
这就是问题所在
and that is the problem.
因为这个  因为你太过愧疚
Because of this, ‭you're so overcome by guilt
你无法忍受再次失去迪恩
that you can't stand to lose Dean again,
他更是不愿失去你
and he could never lose you.
所以你们不选择世界
And so instead of choosing the world,
而是选择彼此
you choose each other,
不管多少无辜者会为此死去
no matter how many innocent people die.
你要在伤害他人这事上教训我吗  就你
You're gonna lecture me about hurting people? You?
你知道我说得对  萨姆
You know I'm right, Sam.
你知道的
You know it.
我知道  如果你想击败黑暗
And I know that if you're gonna beat the Darkness,
你必须准备赴死
you have to be ready to die.
你得准备好看着你所爱的人死去
You have to be ready to watch the people you love die.
很久以前  你是能为大业战斗的
A long time ago, you could've fought the good fight, kid,
但现在不行了
but not anymore.
你赢不了了  萨姆  你不够强大
You can't win this one, Sam. You're just not strong enough.
你就够吗
And you are?
杀人挣钱是我的本行
Hey, snapping necks and cashing checks... that's what I do.
这多好啊
Isn't this nice?
一起度过美好时光
Spending quality time.
您的茶泡好了
Your tea is ready.
可算好了
Finally.
听上去是很不错
That does sound lovely.
您要什么样的茶
How do you take it?
加蜂蜜和一点牛奶
Honey and a splash of milk.
有其母必有其子
Like mother, like son.
失陪
Excuse me.
我得去吐一吐
I need to go vomit.
快点回来  亲爱的
Hurry back, dear.
我并不希望如此  被我同类仇视
I never wanted this, you know, to be hated by my own kind.
我并不...
I never...
-不  我不恨你  卡西迪奥  -谢谢
- Oh, no, I don't hate you, Castiel. - Thank you.
我们有很多共同之处
I mean, ‭we have a lot in common.
我们的名字押韵  这是一点
Our names rhyme, and that's a big one.
我穿风衣也很好看
I look good in a trench coat, too.
而且我们都可有可无
And we're both expendable.
什么
Excuse me?
所以你才被派来  不是吗
Uh, well, that's why we're here, right?
我是个查数的  你...
I'm a number cruncher, and... and you...
我说了  我听过好多事
Like I said, I've heard the stories.
你帮忙
You help,
但萨姆和迪恩·温彻斯特才是真英雄
but Sam and Dean Winchester are the real heroes.
如果黑暗还活着  她肯定很生气
So, if the Darkness is still alive, and she's pissed,
她杀了我们  也无所谓了
and she kills us, no big loss.
是啊  或许我们并不那么重要
So, sure, maybe ‭we're not super important,
但我们能完成工作
but we do the job.
是吧
You know?
我觉得这还是值得尊敬的
I think there's nobility in that.
来吗
Coming?
我就来
I'll catch up.
欢迎来到地狱
Welcome to hell.
-萨姆呢  -别担心萨姆
- Where's Sam? - Oh, don't worry about Sam.
抱歉  你认识我吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Have you met me?
路西法需要小鹿
I mean, ‭Lucifer needs the moose.
他不会杀他...的吧
He's not gonna kill him... probably.
你对抗魔鬼
You versus the devil?
相信我  有更轻松的自杀方式
Trust me, there's easier ways of committing suicide.
我们得专注对付罗威娜
We need to focus on Rowena.
好啊  我们杀了她吧
Okay, great, let's kill her.
恐怕说的容易做的难
Ah, easier said than done, I'm afraid,
而且我们需要母亲把魔鬼关回去
and we need mother to slam the devil back in his hole.
她会配合吗
Well, is she gonna play ball?
她没有选择
She doesn't have a choice.
这叫女巫捕手
It's called a witchcatcher.
大部分在宗教法庭后被毁
Most of them were destroyed after the inquisition,
但比莉还是找到了
but, uh, Billie came through.
嗯  她可讨喜了
Yeah, she's a peach.
这东西干嘛的
What does it do?
你会喜欢的
Oh, you're gonna love this.
安布里奥
Ambriel.
卡西迪奥
Castiel.
阿玛拉
Amara.
你对她做了什么
What did you do to her?
我吃了她
I consumed her.
她的能量  她的火花
Her grace, her spark,
她的记忆  一切
her memories... everything.
她
She...
她真是恰到好处
Oh, she really hit the spot.
不是吧
Seriously?
天堂重拳出击
I mean, heaven brought the thunder,
都没怎么擦破我的皮
and it barely even scratched my paint job,
但你拿着一把小尖刀
but you and a shiny knife?
嗯  肯定有用
Sure, that's gonna work.
你觉得我怕死吗
You think I'm afraid to die?
我知道你怕死
I know you are.
你一股恐惧和自我厌恶的味儿
You reek of fear and self-loathing.
吓人啊
Scary.
她说得对
She's right, you know.
你是可有可无
You are expendable...
而且软弱
And weak.
上帝为什么那么青睐你
And why God took ‭a special interest in you,
我真是无法理解
I'll never understand.
我哥哥一向不会看人
My brother always did have horrible taste in men.
动手吧
Just do it.
蓝眼睛
Blue eyes...
你都不值得我浪费力气
You aren't even worth the effort.
无意冒犯  但你看上去有点累
And, no offense, ‭but you look a bit used up.
而且
Plus...
我有事需要你做
I have a job for you.
迪恩怎么样了
How's Dean?
什么
Pardon?
告诉你  亲爱的
Little tip, love.
你下次去制定秘密计划
The next time you go about making secret plans,
先看下口袋
check your pockets.
我得去吐一吐
I need to go vomit.
快点回来  亲爱的
Hurry back, dear.
你听到了
You heard.
都听到了
Everything.
不过无所谓了
Not that it matters.
什么意思  小子
What does that mean, big boy?
告诉你  母亲
A little tip, mother.
别喝讨厌你的人给你的茶
Never accept a cup of tea from someone who loathes you.
把这东西拿开
Get this bloody thing off of me!
我倒想  但是这东西能让你做我的奴隶
Oh, I would, but this bloody thing makes you my slave.
单脚跳
Hop on one foot.
得了  费格斯
Please, Fergus.
我不知道你以为你在玩什么
I don't know what kind of oedipal fifty shades
变态的恋母游戏  但你如果以为我会...
you think you're playing at, but if you think for a second...
该死
Bollocks.
好了  我们去吧
All right, let's do this.
萨姆
Now, Sam...
我知道这些一时不好接受
I know this is a lot to take in,
如果你需要
so if you need to
花点时间去想想  也没事
take some time and noodle on it, that's cool.
但是  世界在终结啊
But, uh, the world is ending,
懂吗  时间不多了
clock ticking and such if you follow me.
你想要我说什么
What do you want me to say?
Y开头ES结尾的那个词
A little word, uh, starts with "Y," Ends in "E-s""
你不喜欢我
Okay, you don't like me.
我懂的  我懂
I get it. I get it.
我有时候也不喜欢自己
Sometimes I don't like me, either.
但加百列和拉斐尔已经死了
But Gabriel and Raphael are dead.
上帝出去抽了包烟就再也没回来了
God went out for a pack ‭of smokes and never came back.
而米迦勒
And Michael?
这么说吧
Well, let's just say
监狱生活并不是很适合米迦勒
prison life hasn't really agreed with Michael.
这些日子  他一般就坐在角落
These days, he's usually sitting in a corner,
唱唱小曲儿以及...自慰
singing show tunes and...touching himself.
所以只有你了
So you're it?
是啊
I'm it!
还有...
And, hey...
我不是什么好人
I-I'm not the good guy.
我们都知道我不是
We -- we both know I'm not,
但是  黑暗
but, uh, the darkness?
她可是万物的终结
She's the end of everything.
但我可以打败她
But I can beat her.
我们可以打败她
We can beat her.
你和我
You and me.
一起
Together.
所以  来吧  萨姆
So, come on, Sam.
做出正确的选择吧
Make the right choice.
再做一次巨大的牺牲  伙计
The big sacrifice one more time, man.
萨姆
Sam.
该去拯救世界了  伙计
It's time to save the world, man.
不
No.
这个能把路西法丢回笼子里的咒语
So this spell is supposed to slam Lucifer back in the box.
要多久能好
How long's this gonna take?
大约五分钟
About five minutes.
除非萨姆同意了
Unless Sam says yes.
假如他同意了呢
And if he does?
假如路西法找到了一具皮囊
If Lucifer finds a vessel,
他就能在人间扎根了
he'll be anchored to earth.
咒语就起不了作用了
The incantation won't work.
那我们就完了
And then we're screwed.
抱歉  陛下  我尽力...
I'm sorry, my lord. I tried to --
小卡
Cass?
真棒  天使来了
Oh, good, the angel's here.
怎么了
What's happened?
阿玛拉  她还...活着
Amara, she's -- she's alive.
她...
She --
她稍来了这条口信
she sent this message.
"我要来了"
"I am coming"?
那是威胁吗
Is that a threat?
还是保证
Or a promise?
你说"不"是什么意思
What do you mean, no?
你听见我说的了
You heard me.
好吧  萨姆
Okay, now, Sam,
我得告诉你  这太自私了  老兄
I got to tell you, this is selfish, man.
-一切都...  -你完了
- Everything that -- - You are done.
结束了
It's over.
还有你知道吗
And you know what?
你嘴皮子功夫很好  真的
You talk a good game. You do.
有几次你都差点把我说动了
Hell, you almost had me sold a few times,
但之后我一想  假如你是对的呢
but then I thought, what if you're right?
假如你说的是实话呢
What if you're telling the truth?
假如你能打败她呢
What -- what if you can beat her?
我能
I can.
但上一次
Even though, last time,
打败她的是你加上另外三个大天使
it took you ‭plus three other archangels.
对了  还有上帝
Oh, yeah, and capital "G," God.
怎么  你是说那个拖后腿的吗
Oh, okay, what, ‭you mean the dead weight?
但就算你搞定了她  然后呢
But let's say you gank her. Then what?
我搬到洛杉矶  破案去
I move to L.A., solve crimes.
错
Wrong.
然后你就要重新发动天启了
Then you go about starting the apocalypse again
因为你是个老油条
because you're an old dog,
而那是你的老把戏
and that's your old trick.
首先  你不能确定
Hey, first off, you don't know that.
其次  就算我那么做了
Second, even if I did,
那也比她打算做的事好
that's better ‭than what she has planned.
是吗
Is it?
真的吗
Really?
因为我是这么觉得的
Because this is what I think.
我觉得无论是谁赢  你还是黑暗
I think that whoever wins, you or the darkness,
其他人都是输
everyone else loses.
所以  不
So, no.
我的答案是"不"
My answer is no.
这不是因为迪恩或者...过去的事
This isn't 'cause of Dean or -- or the past.
而是因为我对我的朋友们  亲人们
This is about me ‭having faith in my friends,
有信心
having faith in my family.
我们会找到解决办法的
We will find a way.
我准备好赴死了
I'm ready to die.
我也准备好看着我爱的人死去了
And I'm ready to watch people I love die.
但我不打算当你的走狗
But I'm not ready to be your bitch.
好吧
Okay.
B计划
Plan "B."
萨姆
Sam?!
不要
Don't!
混球
Hey, ass-butt!
迪恩
Dean.
以及另一个
Uh, the other one.
欢迎加入派对
Welcome to the party.
害怕吗
Scared?
一点都不
Not even a little.
这样的时刻  气氛是最重要的
Moments like this, it's all about ambience.
我可以打败黑暗
I can beat the darkness.
我  只有我
Me, only me.
这两人算什么玩意
Who are these two?
他俩就是大猩猩
They're a couple of apes.
你知道我是对的  卡西迪奥
You know I'm right, Castiel.
你知道的
You know it.
你想那样玩吗
You want to play that way?
-我们赢不了的  -我们不用赢
- We can't win. - We don't have to win.
我们只需要撑几分钟就好
We've just got to last a few minutes.
你出手像个人类似的
You hit like a human.
好了  萨姆
All right, Sam.
我会让你很好选
I'm gonna make this real easy for you.
要么说出那个"好"
You say the magic word...
要么你哥哥就死
...or your brother dies,
我们都知道你不会看着他死
and we both know you won't let that happen.
[咒语]
那么  有遗言吗
So? Last words?
不用谢
You're welcome.
有人说吗
Anyone?
不说你咬我啊
Bite me.
我可以让她咬你的
I can make her do that.
现在怎么办
So, what now?
关于黑暗吗
About the Darkness?
不知道
No clue.
-我们会想到办法的  -或者尖叫着死去
- We'll figure it out. - Or die screaming.
这真是一场灾难  现在都结束了
This has been a horrible train wreck, so we're done.
组合  结束
Team-up over.
那她呢
What about her?
她留下
She stays.
你们其他人  滚出地狱
The rest of you lot, get the hell out of hell.
你没事吧
You all right?
我想是的
I think so.
我会没事的
I will be.
要我送你一程吗
Want me to give you a lift?
不用  你们俩先走
No, you two go on ahead.
我就来
I'll catch up.
好
Okay.
他还好吗
Is he all right?
今天够呛
Tough day.
是啊  可不是嘛
Yeah, tell me about it.
你还好吗
You good?
不知道
I don't know.
如果路西法说的是真的怎么办
I mean, what if Lucifer was telling the truth?
-如果他  -不  老弟
- You know, what if he's the -- - No, dude.
黑暗是糟糕
Darkness is bad.
她加上魔鬼
Her and the devil?
那就是噩梦
That's a nightmare.
母亲
Mother?
你为什么恨我
Why do you hate me?
我恨你  是因为当我看着你的眼睛
I hate you because when I look into your eyes,
我看到了曾经的我
I see the woman I used to be,
在没有魔法  巫师团之前
before magic, before the coven,
我还什么都不是  只是革匠的女儿罗威娜
when I was nothing but Rowena, the tanner's daughter.
一个苍白  胆怯的小女孩
A pale, scared, little girl
散发着污秽和死亡的气息
who smelled of filth and death.
我恨你
I hate you...
因为你出生时
because when you were born,
你父亲说他爱我
your father said he loved me.
然后他回到了他奢华的家中  他正妻身边
Then he went back to his grand wife and his grand house
而我则可怜地半死不活地躺在草垫上
whilst I lay pathetic ‭and half-dead on a straw mat,
我的大腿沾满鲜血
my thighs slick with blood.
我恨你
I hate you...
因为如果我不恨
Because if I didn't...
我就会爱你
I'd love you.
但是爱  爱是弱点
But love -- love is weakness.
我永远不要再脆弱
And I'll never be weak again.
卡西迪奥
Castiel.
再猜猜
Guess again.
不
No.
有遗言吗
Last words?
你真的能打败她吗
Can you really beat her?
-我可以  -那么好
- I can. - ‭Then, yes.
路西法
Lucifer.
我回来了  宝贝
I'm back, baby!
不可能  你念完了咒语
It can't be. You finished the spell.
但如果他已经在另一个皮囊里
But if he was already in another vessel...
漏洞
Loophole.
见鬼
Bloody hell.
罗威娜
Rowena.
陛下
My liege.
你知道
You know...
你为我做的  我永远不会忘记
What you've done for me, I'll never forget it.
那是我的荣幸
'twas my honor.
是啊
Yes.
It was.
你理应得到奖励
You deserve a reward.
或是  我恩宠的
Or some little token...
小小表示
of my affection.
谢谢您
I thank you.
有一个小问题
Just one teensy, tiny little question.
还有别人能打开笼子吗
Can anyone else open the cage?
只有我
Just me.
很好
Good.
好了
Okay.
我们聊聊吧
Let's chat.